Guide to the Dick Thornburgh Papers, 1932- AIS.1998.30.22
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Awards, Gifts and Memorabilia, 1950-2007; XXII.
  - Governor of Pennsylvania, 9.
    - Gift: Red velvet encased bronze medal inscribed: "March of Peace toward the 21st century: The World Peace Cultural Festival, August 14, 1983
    - Gift: Boxed sterling silver Franklin Mint medal and stand"United Nations 1981 Peace Medal"
    - Gift: Red, white, blue ribbon suspended Medal: "Edinboro University, 29th National Wheelchair Games", June 11-15, 1985
    - Gift: Black boxed gold Franklin mint Medal: "The Temple Centennial, 1894-1984"
    - Gift: Royal blue boxed gold badge on ribbon: "PA. Police Combat Ass'n"
    - Gift: Brown boxed small paperweight: "Neoplan, United States Attorney Corporation, Plant VI, 6-6-85 Honey Brook, PA"
    - Gift: Small clear paperweight: "Temple University Hospital Groundbreaking: March 8, 1983" with small celebratory shovel encased
    - Gift: Another similar clear paperweight: "Phoenix Contact Groundbreaking", July 13, 1984
    - Gift: Clear boxed distinguished service metal pin: "American Legion"
    - Gift: Small clear paperweight containing "The PA Lottery daily number ticket: Number 666" – famous due to fraud later identified! [This may be the original ticket (?)], April 24, 1980
    - Gift: Black leather case enclosed gold medal on ribbon from Lion's Lodge and inscribed on reverse: "Presented to Richard Thornburgh, Governor of Pennsylvania by Joseph L. Wroblewski, President 1985-6"
    - Gift: Boxed bronze "Space Columbia medallion; Rockwell International; Shuttle Orbiter; America's Space Transportation System"
    - Gift: Small clear paperweight enclosing a shot gun shell (?), with small plaque: "Governor Thornburgh/The One And Only!/NH8F Day, 1982/Buss Peters"
    - Gift: Interestingly boxed stand with clear plaque with coin, "In commemoration of your Visit / Han Kyu Kim, President of Holt Children's Services, Inc.", March 11, 1985
    - Gift: Boxed rather fragile award from "Girl Scout Council, Inc., 1979"; Piece of Talus Rock on marble base; to Governor Richard Thornburgh.
    - Gift: Marble paperweight with bronze Medal: Delaware Valley College, brass plate: "Student Center Groundbreaking", September 11, 1982
    - Gift: Red "American" box containing miniature tools, and note from "a coal miner" from Spangler, PA. Small pick and shovel, 1980
    - Gift: Brass small "card" inscribed: "Volunteer Fire Association of Cambria County: This certifies that Governor Thornburgh is a LIFE MEMBER of the above association", September 28, 1981
    - Gift: Pewter heavy round medal from Allegheny Valley Hospital, in blue cloth bag, November 11, 1983
    - Gift: Boxed medal on pin with ribbons: "Honored Guest, Dick Thornburgh, Governor of PA, 1984 Republican National Convention"
    - Gift: Blue boxed brass medallion: Western Connecticut State University / Governor Dick Thornburgh, CONEG, 1985
    - Gift: Two velvet boxed Rotary International Paul Harris Fellow medallions, with chains; one received June 1984, from the Rotary Club of York, PA. Other of unknown date.
    - Gift: What looks to be base only of an award: Presented to Governor Dick Thornburgh in appreciation of his visit to Erie on the occasion of the first presentation of the GOVERNORS CUP TROPHY,"We Love Erie," Louis J. Tullio, Mayor, August 24, 1979
    - Gift: Metal Idaho License Plate: "PA – GOV, Governors' Conference, 1985
    - Gift: Metal License Plate: "Governor Thornburgh, Pennsylvania, Republican Governors' Conference, Philadelphia, 1980
    - Gift: Small gold coin: Disabled American Veterans 50th: 1932-1982; Greater Pittsburgh Dept of Pa, Chapter 8 [in envelope]
    - Gift: Small wooden plaque: Governor's Timber Conference, 1983 (Oversize 147)
    - Gift: Great Lakes Governors Economic Summit [large & heavy], May 1983
    - Gift: Penn State University Nittany Lion "statue" on base, "Governor Thornburgh A Friend of Agriculture"
    - Gift: Lion's Club International: Clear paperweight with lion inside, 1984-1985
    - Gift: Anthracite plaque picturing mule pulling coal car, "Governor Dick Thornburgh," [interesting], 1982 (Oversize 148)
    - Gift: U.S. Steel Homestead works; heavy steel plinth "sculpture", 1979
    - Gift: National Association of Water Companies Award for Excellence to Governor Dick Thornburgh [heavy], June 6, 1984
    - Gift: Brass Sherlock Holmes figure on plinth: "To Governor Dick Thornburgh, for outstanding service…to motivate youngsters to read while raising funds for MS research and patient services", September 1981 (Oversize 149)
    - Gift: Valley Forge Country, Convention and Visitors Bureau "Hats off Award" to Governor Dick Thornburgh [funny], 1986
    - Gift: Bronze fallen horse figure on base, "Gaudenzia Outstanding Achievement Award to Governor and Mrs. Thornburgh" [remarkable], April 23, 1983
    - Gift: Handsome ceramic name plate framed in wood; "Governor and Mrs. Richard L. Thornburgh" (Oversize 150)
    - Gift: Small bronze train on wooden base: Altoona, PA, April 24, 1982
    - Gift: Proctor Silex toaster on wooden base: Honorable Richard Thornburgh [nifty], June 20, 1979
    - Gift: Chapman Quarry Slate with Indian figure embossed, September 18, 1986
    - Gift: Mirrored PA shaped award "To Governor Dick Thornburgh, a great Governor, who gets things done!"; From Nate [Smith], 1978-1986
    - Gift: Boeing Model 234 Helicopter, Governor Richard L. Thornburgh [Very interesting, and rather large], May 1, 1986 (Oversize 151)
    - Gift; Armco Tubular Division: Metal tube on base [pencil and pen holder], November 1981
    - Gift: Anthracite figure of coal miner, on base, Awarded by King Coal Association [poignant figure], November 8, 1979
    - Gift: Infrastructure Award for "foresight and leadership… toward rebuilding our crumbling infrastructure" Constructors Assn. of W. PA, January 17, 1986 (Oversize 152)
    - Gift: "…For commitment to and support of excellence in education" Aldan Elementary School, January 23, 1986
    - Gift: …For outstanding contribution to 1986 Florida Republican Candidates, August 12, 1986
    - Gift: PA American Legion Patriots Award, July 11, 1986
    - Gift: Greater Pittsburgh Chamber of Commerce… outstanding service and accomplishments [background picture of the city], January 5, 1987
    - Gift: Society of Undergraduate Engineers at University of Pittsburgh Johnstown, "First Engineer of PA", 1986
    - Gift: United Veterans Council of Philadelphia… distinguished public service award, "…for unique public service as US Attorney General and Governor…" [they must be referring to his years as US Attorney of W. PA not AG], Nov. 11, 1986
    - Gift: Appreciation…welcoming speaker…Convention of PA League of Cities, June 1986
    - Gift: Small framed medal picturing signing of Declaration of Independence on occasion of 200 anniversary by Independence Hall Association [nice] (Oversize 153)
    - Gift: Pewter Liberty Bell
    - Gift: Groundbreaking of Bidwell Training Center, illustration, March, 19, 1985
    - Gift: Bicentennial flag in honor of the Constitution of the US celebration for 1987 [From the designer]
    - Gift: "License Plate," National Governors Association, Grand Lake, Oklahoma, 74th annual meeting, "'THORNBURGH' Pennsylvania", 1982
    - Gift: Faucet and Pipe on marble base, Effluent Treatment Facilities Dedication, To Governor Dick Thornburgh [nifty], September 30, 1982
    - Gift: Heavy white brick: "Center lane Brick, Squirrel Hill Tunnel, PA Department of Transportation, District 11-0, Parkway East Rehabilitation, 1981-1982
    - Gift: Pelican Ceramic Statue with base: "Governor and Mrs. Dick Thornburgh, Republican Governors Conference, New Orleans, LA, FRAGILE, 1981 (Oversize 154)
    - Plaque: Lehigh County Republican Committee, Governor Dick Thornburgh, "…outstanding 8 Years of service as Governor 1979-1987" (Oversize 155)
    - Plaque: Governor Dick Thornburgh "Time, Talent and Commitment to founding and Support of State System of Higher Education...Board of Governors of the System", January 1987
    - Plaque: Wooden base with large handsome "ring-able" brass bell. To Governor Dick Thornburgh…by W. Wilson Goode on behalf of Philadelphia Port Corporation, January 12, 1987
    - Plaque: To Governor Dick Thornburgh for leadership in field of victim assistance by Natl. Organization for Victim Assistance, 1980 (Oversize 156)
    - Plaque: Dick Thornburgh, Governor, designated Honorary Trooper PA State Police "…unfailing support", January 13, 1987
    - Plaque: Richard L. Thornburgh, "…attention to needs of conservation and preservation of natural resources… Garden Club Federation", 1987
    - Plaque: Hon Dick Thornburgh…leadership in construction of Riverside Stadium and return of professional baseball to Harrisburg [Nice emblem of batter], April 11, 1987
    - Plaque: Richard Lewis Thornburgh…outstanding support for Greater Pittsburgh Literacy Council, 1987
    - Plaque: From PA State Assn of Township Supervisors…a friend of township government whose work reflects our mutual belief that "the closer government is to the people, the more efficient that government will be", April 13, 1987
    - Plaque: PA Assoc for Adult Continuing Education PAACE… appreciation for leadership in Challenge of Adult Literacy and Passage of Act 143, undated
    - Plaque: Military Order Purple Heart of United States Attorney…dedication and contributions toward improving care of PA veterans, 1986
    - Plaque: Letter, from James A. Baker III…re leadership of 1986 State Government Savings Bonds Campaign, December 10, 1986
    - Plaque: 1987 Entrepreneur of the Year by Arthur Young/VENTURE Magazine, Richard Lewis Thornburgh
    - Plaque: Flat heavy metal piece, "First Heat, July 18-84" (Oversize 157)
    - Plaque: Bronze statue/sculpture by artist – but no ID, Policeman holding a child on a wooden base [event unknown]
    - Plaque: Large wooden gavel with copper "label": "presented to Governor by Matthew J. Ryan, Speaker of the House, November 30, 1982
    - Gift: Barnabas "Hance Award," Heavy etched glass on nice wooden base with copper plaque "Dick Thornburgh 1987" [Governor transition] (Oversize 158)
    - Cartoon: State Store Cartoon (Oversize 159)
    - Cartoon: Governor's Mansion: Ginny Thornburgh not running for Governor
    - Gift: Baseball caps, Italian American Police Officers and Mass. Assn. of Italian American Police Officers, Inc. 196H. ["1968" appears to be an historical reference]
    - Award: HEAVY metal name plate:"Dick Thornburgh Governor" on wooden base, top edge reads: "Statue of Liberty Restoration." Given by Carpenters Technology Corporation, Reading, PA, who participated in the restoration of Lady Liberty, 1985 (Oversize 160)
    - Award: Boehm porcelain bald eagle head and stand; Treaty of Paris celebration, 1783-1983; Chamber of Commerce, Princeton area [Valuable! and FRAGILE], October 15, 1983 (Oversize 162)
    - Gift: Phoenix Contact, Round black blown glass world globe commemorative paperweight. Gift commemorating 100th Anniversary of Phoenix Contact, Inc given on occasion of groundbreaking ceremony, July 1984 (Oversize 164)
    - Gift: Fragile porcelain plate with stand in box from Sun Yun Suan, Premier, Republic of China
    - Gift: Marble paperweight with seal of Yale University Timothy Dwight College, Chubb Fellow, November 7-8, 1985
    - Gift: License Plate: PA 1 Presidential Inaugural [Portland], 1985
    - Gift: License Plate: National Governors Association 75th Annual Meeting, "Thornburgh: Pennsylvania", 1983
    - Plaque: Glass triangular plaque on wooden base: "Keystone Citizenship Award" from PA Association of Broadcasters, 1986
    - Gift: Medallion of Distinction, Framed coin on velvetUniversity of Pittsburgh Bicentennial – 1787-1987To Honorable Richard L. Thornburgh, February 23, 1988 (Oversize 167)
    - Gift: Round metal plate with Mack Truck dog emblem rising from it, Governor Thornburgh, undated (Oversize 172)
    - Gift: Gold boxed Gideon Bible with gold lettering"Gideon Bible to Dick Thornburgh," Presented by The Gideons
    - Gift: Paul Harris Fellow Medal in velvet box, Rotary Foundation of Rotary International, undated
    - Gift: Silver Box, Governor Dick Thornburgh, [Honorary] Doctor of Law: Honoris Causa, Indiana University of Pennsylvania, May 4, 1983
    - Gift: Pewter mug (dented and scratched), PA Gas Association, to Honorable Dick Thornburgh, May 11-13, 1983
    - Gift: Crystal mounted clock, Governor Dick ThornburghThanks and Good Luck, Lawrence County Republicans, April 30, 1986
    - Gift: Round silver tray, Elizabethtown Chamber of Commerce, In appreciation, Governor Richard Thornburgh, January 30, 1980
    - Gift: Round porcelain plate, Governor Richard Thornburgh, To commemorate your visit to Charleroi, 'Still the Magic City' Charleroi Central Business District, Mayor Fred McLuckie and council members, May 2, 1983
  - Institute of Politics, 10.
    - Gifts: Two posters with seal of Dunster House, Harvard, inscribed Dick Thornburgh, and second one Virginia Thornburgh (Oversize 127)
    - Certificate: Richard L. Thornburgh, Honorary West Virginian "in recognition of having demonstrated an expression of goodwill and respect for the people of the Mountain State and is therefore presented with this certificate of friendship" [Very decorative], November 3, 1987
    - Gift: IOP Forum Posters [Complete set], June 1987 – July 1988
    - Honorary Degree: Doctor of Laws, Carnegie Mellon University [With framed citation], May 15, 1988
    - Honorary Degree: Doctor of Laws, Suffolk University [Degree and citation certificate], June 5, 1988
    - Cartoon: Thornburgh for President Exploratory Committee (Oversize 159)
    - Cartoon: Crane with Elephant (Attorney General Dick Thornburgh) and Teamsters
    - Certificate: Florida Tax Watch, seal of Florida, October 14, 1987 (Oversize 161)
    - Plaque: Inscribed red medal wording: "Wm Penn Society at Gannon University, Erie, PA "Acknowledges Hon. Dick Thornburgh a distinguished Pennsylvanian who has Served the Commonwealth of PA with dedication and distinction", March 14, 1988 (Oversize 167)
  - Attorney General of United States, 11.
    - Photo: Former Attorney General Meese with Attorney General Dick Thornburgh, Meese portrait unveiling event, July 25, 1991 (Oversize 1)
    - Certificate: To Attorney General from men and women of the drug administration with narrative of drug bust, November 24, 1991 (Oversize 5)
    - Gift: Autographed Department of Justice Seal, US Attorney for Northern District, Illinois [Gift to Attorney General when leaving office [Unframed, matted on foam] (Oversize 12)
    - Photograph: Large unframed matted photo Attorney General [nice]
    - Photograph: Attorney General shaking hands with President Salinas of Mexico
    - Photograph: Group in United States Attorney Office, Florida, Bob Genzman, United States Attorney (Oversize 13)
    - Photograph: Framed night view of Dept. of Justice and Capital given by United States Attorneys, "Presented to Thornburgh, Attorney General of U.S. '89 – '91; on behalf of the USAs and Executive Office for USAs with grateful appreciation for your support and leadership during your tenure as Attorney General of United States of America" (Oversize 14)
    - Photograph: Framed with poem from Brock Brauer (Attorney General's speech writer) [humorous celebration poem ".... infield play"] (Oversize 15)
    - Photo Album: US Border Patrol, San Diego sector of the INS [includes some great ones, oversized in color], October 25, 1988 (Oversize 16)
    - Gift: Small US flag with stand and hardware. Scout Salute – Allegheny/Lunch-o-ree; Thornburgh Keynote Speaker, June 21, 1990 (Oversize 17)
    - Photograph: Attorney General Dick Thornburgh at mike on steps of Supreme Court Building surrounded by reporters [Great and significant image! Very large, foam backed], November 2, 1988 (Oversize 28)
    - Certificate: President Reagan appoints Thornburgh to ACIR [Advisory Commission on Intergovernmental Relations], September 13, 1988 (Oversize 29)
    - Photograph of President GHW Bush and Attorney General Thornburgh, Informal by fireplace in Oval Office[Nice!] (Oversize 30)
    - Honorary Degree: Doctor of Laws, University of Scranton[citation included], June 14, 1990 (Oversize 31)
    - Certificate: California Assembly Resolution, June 14, 1990 (Oversize 32)
    - Award: Agudath Israel 1991 Humanitarian Award, May 12, 1991 (Oversize 33)
    - Award: Gold Medal to Attorney General from PA Association of Broadcasters [Glass obelisk on base], October 14, 1990 (Oversize 35)
    - Plaque: SEA, October 19, 1988 (Oversize 36)
    - Certificate: Commendation from Dade County, Florida,to Distinguished Visitor Richard Thornburgh, Attorney General of the United States [Framed], October 24, 1990 (Oversize 38)
    - Award: Bob Hope 5-Star Civilian Award from Valley Forge Military Academy and Junior College to Honorable Dick Thornburgh for Distinguished Service to the United States of America [framed], May 7, 1989 (Oversize 39)
    - Award: Kansas City Honorary Citizen, October 24, 1990 (Oversize 40)
    - Award: Man, Woman and Child Statue to Attorney General for the "Pro-family policies of the United States Justice Department, Knights of Columbus Public Forum, Hollywood, California [brass statuette on wooden base], February 9, 1991 (Oversize 42)
    - Gift: Congressional Fire Services Institute: To Thornburgh for service to men and women of the American Fire and Emergency Services, 3rd Annual National Fire and Emergency Services Dinner, Washington, D.C. [Metal megaphone and Separate wooden base, together as OS 43], April 30, 1991 (Oversize 43)
    - Plaque: "To Thornburgh in appreciation for all your efforts and active support for the work of the Division. Environment and Natural Resources Division, [Large wooden "slice"from tree trunk], August 15, 1991 (Oversize 48)
    - Award: Framed engraved on metal etching of University of Pittsburgh School of Law, awarded on occasion of Caplan Lecture at School of Law, April 3, 1990 (Oversize 52)
    - Photograph: Attorney General in classroom at teacher's desk with kids in front [Large, foam backed] (Oversize 117)
    - Photograph: Attorney General at teacher's desk with blackboard with his name behind him [Large, foam backed]
    - Photograph: Attorney General close up – DOJ seal partially behind him, no glasses, good picture [Large, foam backed]
    - Photograph: Attorney General with Stanley Cup Penguins shirt [Large, foam backed]
    - Photograph: Attorney General with DOJ Seal, at podium speaking, with President GHW Bush looking on. [When newly elected President Bush reappointed Thornburgh Attorney General; excellent photo- large], November 21, 1988 (Oversize 118)
    - Gift: Pastel drawing of Dick Thornburgh arguing Payne v. Tennessee before Supreme Court, by Carole Kabrin, ABC News [Thornburgh without glasses, Supreme Court Justice in background], April 24, 1991 (Oversize 122)
    - Flag: Handsome DOJ flag (c. 2' x 3.5') given as parting gift by Attorney General Staff, 1991 (Oversize 123)
    - Flag: Huge fringed flag, most likely to be for flag pole: c. 6' x 4'. Handsome. Royal blue background. From US Attorneys to Attorney General. Flagpole finial and gold cord included
    - Photograph: Color photograph of Attorney General Thornburgh with Martin Lee, (Hong Kong connection) (Oversize 124)
    - Photograph: Color photograph of Dick and Ginny Thornburgh and John and Janet Ashcroft (former Attorney General)
    - Photograph: Color photograph of Attorney General Thornburgh with Paul O'Neill, Ex-Alcoa CEO and U.S. Treasury Secretary, from Pittsburgh
    - Photograph: Color photograph of Ken Starr, AG DT, and Robert Fiske. Starr was Solicitor General when DT was AG. Fiske a noted litigator
    - Photograph: Color photograph of DT with Louis Freeh, 10th Director of the FBI
    - Certificate: Attorney General flew on Air Force One, from President Bush, March 22, 1989 (Oversize 127)
    - Award: Conference of Chief Justices, Resolution of Appreciation to Attorney General [Leather cover], August 16, 1990
    - Gift: Christmas cards to Ginny and Dick Thornburgh from President and Mrs. Bush [oversized, autographed, handsome], 1989-1991
    - Honorary Degree: Franklin Marshall College, Doctor of Humane Letters, October 20, 1988 (Oversize 130)
    - Honorary Degree: George Washington University, National Law Center, Doctor of Laws, May 21, 1989
    - Honorary Degree: Catholic University of America, Doctor of Laws, May 26, 1990
    - Stamps: Leather Folders enclosing full page of first issue stamps, with accompanying letter from Postmaster General, Anthony M. Frank, to Richard Thornburgh, Attorney General, 1988, partial 1989 (Oversize 132)
    - Stamps: Leather Folders enclosing full page of first issue stamps, with accompanying letter from Postmaster General, Anthony M. Frank, to Richard Thornburgh, Attorney General, 1989 and 1990 (Oversize 133)
    - Stamps: Leather Folders enclosing full page of first issue stamps, with accompanying letter from Postmaster General, Anthony M. Frank, to Richard Thornburgh, Attorney General, Partial 1990, 1991 (Oversize 134)
    - Plaque: Pennsylvanians vs. Pornography, Recognizes service of Richard Thornburgh as US Attorney General and his commitment to upholding the obscenity laws: RAAP Conference, October 1989 (Oversize 159)
    - Award: Flat Etched Glass award on wooden base (c.8"x6"): "Proclaiming and Protecting Human Dignity – Dick Thornburgh – National Leadership Award. From The Religious Alliance Against Pornography [Flame of Compassion also etched on the glass], 1991
    - Photograph: Attorney General with Assistant Attorneys General in Conference Room (Oversize 161)
    - Gift: Photograph of Attorney General Dick Thornburgh seated in front row, with United States Attorney's Office attorneys, Pittsburgh
    - Gift: Framed pencil sketch of Dick Thornburgh, "Paris, Affaire Maamar – Assises Speciale" [Dick Thornburgh was present in courtroom at the time], December 1989
    - Plaque: Clock on plaque to Dick Thornburgh US Attorney General in appreciation for leadership and friendship, from Federal Bureau of Prisons [nice] (Oversize 162)
    - Gift: Incredibly heavy large [long] carved marble name plate with lettering in gold script: "Dick Thornburgh, U.S. Attorney General" [Very distinguished] (Oversize 163)
    - Gift: DOJ United States Attorney Office, Northern District of Ohio [paper weight]
    - Plaque: DOJ Postal Inspection Service to Attorney General [handsome looking with stamps]
    - Plaque: From United States Attorneys to Attorney General[handsome night photo of DOJ]
    - Plaque: From Men and Women of offices of United States Attorneys for "outstanding support of law enforcement", August 15, 1991 (Oversize 164)
    - Plaque: Outstanding Citizens Award to Dick Thornburgh"…outstanding contributions to your profession and the community" Palo Alto Jaycees, March 23, 1990 (Oversize 167)
    - Plaque: "In Recognition of a Long Time Friend"United States Attorney General Richard ThornburghPennsylvania Easter Seal Society, "Providing the Power to Overcome/ Serving Persons with Disabilities", November 1990
    - Award: Upright etched glass rectangle on wooden baseNational Government Leaders Against Drunk Driving Award To Honorable Dick Thornburgh, Department of Justice By MADD, February 19, 1991 (Oversize 168)
    - Award: Vertical etched glass illuminated plinth on wooden base, handsome; National Foundation for People with Disabilities Mentor Award, Presented to Attorney General Dick Thornburgh for his wise counsel Americans with Disabilities Act, 1990, 1991
    - Award: Brass Gold Apple Award to Dick Thornburgh, Attorney General of the U.S. a great friend of literacy Freedom to Read Conference, Ottawa, CA ["golden apple" in clear cube on wooden base], October 14-17, 1990